這才是去海邊的樣子
MacGYVER: Now, this is what goin' to the beach is all about.
( women shouting )
外面有幾個美女
Boy, there's some fine-lookin' women out there, huh?
-你有望遠鏡嗎？ -有, 在廚房
You got those binoculars?
Yeah, in the kitchen.
話說回來
MacGYVER: On the other hand,
我從不覺得拯救女將軍 是海灘樂趣
rescuin' a lady general
has never been my idea of beach fun.
( doorknob rattles )
好了
看看有什麼可用的
All right, let's see what we've got to work with.
這是好的開始
Okay, this seems to be a good start.
我只需要他們分心幾秒鐘
All I need is a few seconds of distraction.
老天, 你看看
Oh, man,
look at that!
（蔬菜油）
我一定要出去看看
Oh, I gotta go outside and check this out.
What the...?
我們走, 快點
Hey, let's go! Come on!
誰在裡面？
Who's in there?
Hey!
( grunting )
看來妳對他們 什麼都沒說吧, 將軍
I'll bet you didn't tell them a thing, huh, General?
我把妳弄出去吧
Let's get you outta here.
手銬, 可惡
Handcuffs! Damn!
( men grunting and shouting )
( grunting )
抓住他
她不見了
She's gone!
( both yell )
( grunting and gasping )
別動
坐下, 別動
Stay! Sit! Stay!
好狗狗
Good dogs.
派克曼, 我是馬蓋先
Yeah, Packman? MacGyver.
你失蹤的女將軍
You know that lady general you lost?
我找到她了
Well, I found her.
馬蓋先 第一季
目標馬蓋先
我真的得重新思考我的人生了
MacGYVER: I really have to rethink my life.
才把女將軍送回五角大廈
I hardly get the lady general back to the Pentagon
就接到紅色警戒的任務
when I get a Code Red priority.
所以我在這個月光照耀的夜晚
So, here I am on a moonlit night starin' down the throat
盯著這座全新的 中東核能精煉廠
of a brand-new Middle Eastern nuclear refining plant
它存在的原因不外乎
put on this good Earth for no other reason
就是要讓某個軍事狂人 炸掉他的鄰居
than to allow some crazy strong man
to blow up his neighbors.
猜猜華府要我做什麼
Guess what Washington asked me to do.
好, 準備好要炸了
All right, ready to blow it.
4點30分來接我
Be at the pickup zone at 0430.
好了
All right.
回到家了, 夠了就是夠了
Home-- enough is enough.
我不會在任何條件下 為任何原因
I will not, under any circumstances
for any reason whatsoever answer the phone...
再接電話了
可能吧
probably... again.
沒錯, 我的確回到家了
Yes, I am definitely home.
什麼事？
Well?
我只是來恭喜你
I just dropped in to congratulate you.
非常謝謝你
Thank you very much.
部裡很感激
The Department is grateful.
不客氣
You're welcome.
我很累了
And I'm very tired.
我不是來派任務給你的
I'm not offering you an assignment.
我是來警告你
I'm giving you a warning.
你成了目標了
You're a target.
那你就要說清楚了
Now, that I'd like spelled out.
你把核能廠處理掉的時候
When you put away that nuclear installation, they ID'd you.
他們認出你了
第二天就放話出去
The contract went out the next day.
他們僱用了阿克斯特
They hired Axminster.
他殺了謝赫哈三, 對吧？
He took out Sheikh Hussein, didn't he?
就在禱告時
Right in the middle of prayers.
把他炸得當場上西天
Blew him straight to Allah
還順道殺了37個人
and killed 37 others along the way.
我們監看這裡的同時 你應該出城去
You oughta get out of town while we, uh, stake this place out.
巴尼, 我的麻煩 我喜歡自己處理
Barney, I like to take care of my own messes.
馬蓋先
MacGyver,
阿克斯特可以為了你 燒光整個街區
Axminster would torch the whole block just to get you.
我可以幫你 弄個安全無虞的住處
Now, I can set up a safe house, full security,
除非你自己有地方
unless, uh, you've got someplace
可以待上幾個星期
you'd like to settle in for a couple of weeks.
其實, 是有趟旅行
You know, there is a kind of a,
我想了一陣子了
a trip I've been toying with.
現在就去吧
Take it now.
只要是能讓你消失的
As long as it spells one word: "lost."
( sighs )
我想我的確該拜訪一個人
I guess I do owe a visit.
是誰？
To who?
這是私事
It's personal, Barney.
好吧, 只要告訴我地點
Okay, just tell me if and where.
我會處理, 上校
I'll handle that, Colonel,
你不需要知道
and you don't need to know where.
你只要把阿克斯特處理好
You just take care of Axminster.
你看看這個
Take a look at this!
什麼？
What?
有個女人被外星人攻擊 還生了外星人寶寶
It says this here lady was attacked by aliens
and had an alien baby.
真的嗎？
No kiddin'?
對, 在阿拉巴馬州
Yeah. In Alabama somewhere.
在那裡外星人是大事
Big on aliens in Alabama.
沒錯, 一堆怪人
No lie.
Full of strange people.
所以我才往北走
That's why I'm goin' North,
回去看看家人
back to see my family for a while.
有道理
Makes sense.
我十歲起就沒見過我外公了
MacGYVER: I hadn't seen my grandfather since I was ten.
他是我僅有的家人
He was all the family I had left,
而我們形同陌路
and we were strangers.
( phone ringing )
我是馬蓋先
MacGYVER: Hi. MacGyver here.
聽到嗶聲後 告訴我你在想什麼
When you hear the beep, let me know what's on your mind.
( beep )
我告訴你我在想什麼, 孩子
JACKSON: I'll let you know what's on my mind, bud.
把電話拿起來 我不喜歡跟機器說話
Pick up that phone and talk to me.
I got no mind for machines.
真是, 你大概不在家
Oh, damn, I guess you aren't there!
我是你的…
This is your...
我是哈利.傑克森
This is Harry Jackson.
The-the clerk from the general store
雜貨店的店員給我這個號碼
brung me up a note with this phone number.
他說你要來看我
He says you're comin' to visit me.
阿克斯特
Axminster!
我只是想告訴你…
JACKSON: And I just want to say...
別過來, 我很忙
don't come.
I'm busy.
你大概已經在路上了
Ah, hell, you're probably on the way here already.
如果你又打去雜貨店
You can phone the general store again.
電話是303-555-7702
It's area code 303, triple-five, double-seven-oh-two.
我立刻去查
I'll try and run that down right away.
真是個美麗的地方
MacGYVER: What a beautiful part of the world.
什麼都有, 就是沒有人
Has everything but people.
我不明白我外公是怎麼了
I got to wonder what happened to my grandfather
為什麼決定這樣離群索居
that made him decide to live in such isolation.
事實上 我甚至懷疑他來不來接我
Actually, I wonder
if he'll even be here to meet me.
WOMAN: There he is...
WOMAN: Well, hop in.
你好, 哈利
Hi, Harry.
你怎麼知道？
How'd you know?
我是不會忘記外公的
I never forget a grandfather.
你長大了
You've grown.
已經過了16、17、18年了吧？
Well, it's been, what, six, 17, 18 years, hasn't it?
我沒注意
I hadn't noticed.
你沒收到我的留言 我想叫你別來
Didn't get my message to you.
I tried to head you off.
你介意我來嗎？
You mind that I came?
( bird squawking )
算了, 你人都到了
Ah, what the hell. You're here.
走吧, 我想在天黑前回到家
Well, come on.
I want to get home before dark.
車燈壞了
Headlights don't work.
你都沒變
You haven't changed.
沒必要, 我也沒打算要
Haven't had to, and I don't plan to.
好
All Right.
( seagull cawing )
好的
All right.
好
Okay.
謝謝
Thanks a lot.
號碼是在科羅拉多小鎮 烏雷的一家雜貨店
The number's a general store
in a little town in Colorado-- Ouray.
哈利.傑克森沒有電話
Harry Jackson doesn't have a phone,
但他們認識他 阿克斯特, 他們知道他住哪裡
but they know him, Axminster.
They know where he lives.
( truck thudding )
你是要摔死我 還是在嚇唬我
You trying to throw me or just scare me?
你老是喜歡聊天
You always did like to talk.
還是那麼強壯, 對吧？
Still tough as a dirty boot, aren't you?
一點都沒錯
You're damn right.
( door squeaking and closing )
怎麼樣
Well?
又濃又熱的黑咖啡, 是嗎
Black, hot and strong, right?
你都記得, 孩子
Nothin' wrong with your memory, bud.
外婆說過
Grandma used to say
除非咖啡濃到讓湯匙立著 否則你是不喝的
you'd never drink a cup of coffee
unless a spoon would stand up in it.
你外婆從不放棄要我文雅些
Grandma never did give up trying to civilize me.
那也許是她唯一做過的蠢事
I guess maybe
that was the only dumb mistake she ever did make.
除了過世之外
Except maybe dyin'.
所以你才離開我們嗎？
Is that why you left us?
你總是一針見血
You always did get right to the point.
你還是一樣
Haven't changed.
是變得不多
Not much.
要咖啡嗎？
Want coffee?
好
Yeah.
你還沒回答我
You didn't answer me.
我離開…
I left...
是因為時候到了
because it was time to leave.
不, 爸死的時候你還在
No, when Dad died, you were there.
你還在陪著我們
I mean, you were... you were there.
我是待了一陣子
I stayed around
for a while.
老天, 我有權過我自己的日子
God, for the love of Mike, boy,
I still had the right to my own life!
可惡, 哈利
Doggone it, Harry,
我介意的是…
你離開的方式
I guess maybe it's... how you did it.
某天早上我醒來, 你就不見了
I wake up one morning, and you're gone.
我不喜歡道別
I never liked good-byes.
我接了在阿拉斯加的一個工程
I
took a job workin'
in construction up in Alaska.
好差事
Good job.
新地方
New country.
所以我去了
So I went.
我估計能定期寄錢…
I figured sending money regular would be more use
對你媽和你 會比我更有用
to you and your mother than I was.
那你估計錯了
You figured wrong.
你的床在那 要走要留隨便你
That's your bunk.
Leave or stay, it's up to you.
我們準備好出發了, 阿克斯特
We're ready to roll, Axminster.
( engines starting )
你想怎麼處理馬蓋先？
How do you want this guy MacGyver?
要死還是活的？
Dead or alive?
死
Dead.
( birds singing )
好吃
It's good.
你來做什麼？
Now, why are you here?
我只是不想再拖延來看你
I guess I just got past puttin' off this visit.
我好幾年沒想過家人了
I haven't thought about family in years.
現在也不怎麼想
Don't really want to now.
哈利, 你脾氣總是這麼硬嗎？
Harry, were you always this hard-nosed?
即便在我小的時候？
Even when I was a kid?
( sighs )
我記得這個
I remember this.
JACKSON: Uh...
這不是我十歲時 做給你的嗎
Didn't I make this for you when I was about ten?
你過生日還是什麼的
For your birthday or something?
( quacking )
很好用
It works good, too.
最好的
Best I ever had.
小屋就在山脊上, 阿克斯特
CARSON: Cabin's at the top of the ridge, Axminster.
分兩路
Then spread out.
我們包抄小屋抓他們
We'll surround the cabin and hit 'em.
準備好要釣魚了嗎？
So, you ready for some fishin'?
我已經去過了 不然早餐怎麼會有魚
I already been.
What do you think we're havin' for breakfast?
拜託, 哈利
Come on, Harry.
是你告訴我 不是為了釣「魚」而「釣魚」
You're the one that used to tell me
you don't fish for fish, you fish for fishin'.
是純粹為「釣魚」而「釣魚」
房子是空的, 阿克斯特
CARSON: Cabin's empty, Axminster!
( birds singing )
真不錯
Nice.
是, 真的很棒
Yeah, it's real nice.
八年前發現這裡
Found this place about eight years ago.
我要待在這裡直到我死
I'm stayin' right here till I die.
你太固執, 不會死
Ah, you're too mean to die.
凡事皆有因果
What goes around comes around.
貨車還在, 他們一定在附近
BLACK: The truck's still here, Axminster.
They got to be close.
我跟媽在感恩節時最想你
You know, I think Mom and I missed you most
around Thanksgiving, Christmas.
還有聖誕節
我記得你會帶我去砍樹
I remember you used to take me out to cut a tree.
別煩了
Stop riding it!
我來這裡讓你那麼難受嗎？
Is my being here
that hard on you?
孩子
Bud,
這話題到此為止
subject is closed.
( fishing line creaking )
我釣到了
I got one.
I got one!
拉上來, 孩子, 小心
JACKSON: I said drag, bud. Watch it.
真不錯
Ah, that's a beaut!
晚餐, 別讓牠溜了
That's for dinner.
Don't let loose of him.
我不會讓牠溜了
I'm not gonna let loose of him.
拿網子來, 哈利
Get the net, Harry.
( gunshot )
搞什麼…
Hey, what the...?
( gunshots )
Aah!
究竟怎麼回事？
What the hell is goin' on?
我等一下跟你說, 快
I'll tell you later. Come on.
你的朋友是誰？
Who are your friends?
哈利, 我沒想到他們會找到這裡
Harry, I didn't think they'd find me here.
他們可能很快就過來了
They'll probably be down here in a minute.
我們走
Let's go!
蘆葦？
JACKSON: Hollow reeds?
MacGYVER: Yeah. We'll make 'em think
對, 要讓他們以為 我們還在水裡
we're still out there in the water.
他們會識破的
They're too smart for that one, boy.
總是要試試
Got to try something.
如果他們真的中計呢, 孩子？
What if they do fall for this stunt of yours, bud?
對我們有什麼好處？
What do we get out of it?
拉開距離
Buy a little distance.
得看他們是否相信 我們躲在蘆葦下面呼吸
All depends on them believin' that it's us
breathin' under these reeds.
有點信心, 哈利
Have a little faith, Harry.
他們到底在哪？
AXMINSTER: Where the hell are they?
在那裡, 那些蘆葦
Down there, those reeds!
開槍
Fire!
( rapid gunfire )
你去看看
You, check it out.
被耍了
They tricked us.
什麼意思？
What are you talking about?
被馬蓋先設計了
MacGyver set us up.
我們去跟阿克斯特說
Let's go tell Axminster.
看來你的朋友在湖的對岸 找到那些蘆葦
Guess your friends found those reeds
over on the other side of the lake.
看吧
你孫子是有點本事的
See, your grandson's got something on the ball.
等一下, 哈利
Hold it, Harry.
這是蕁科植物, 很毒的
It's a plant from the Urtica family.
Strong stuff.
一點點在血液中
One dab in the bloodstream hits the neural system
就會影響神經系統 昏迷好幾個小時
and a guy's out for hours.
吹箭？
Blow gun?
我就是在想那類的東西
I was thinking along those lines.
Ah.
哈利, 我們唯一的問題
The only problem we got, Harry,
要把他們擊昏, 得要射得準
in order for me to knock them out,
I'm gonna have to hit them just right.
正中頸子
Right in the neck.
要是射偏了呢？
What if you miss?
好, 給我
Okay, here we go.
現在吹箭有了
HARRY: Now we got a blow gun,
也許做些腳印 引他們找到我們
maybe help to make kind of a trail for them to track us.
等一下, 他們的足跡通往小溪
BLACK: Hold it.
Their trail leads down to the stream.
怎麼回事？
Hey, what's the matter?
Hey, hey, what's...?
怎麼…
( grunting )
( yells )
做得好
Nice.
要正中目標才對
Gotta hit them just right.
哈利, 我們能從這走嗎？
Harry, can we get out this way?
看來我們沒有選擇
Don't seem to have a lot of choice.
是沒有
No.
等一下
Hold it!
Hold it right there, bud.
等等, 孩子, 你停不停啊？
Will you stop?
現在給我停下來！
Now wait a minute!
我說別走
I said hold it right there!
你是做什麼的, 孩子？
Who are you, bud?
這究竟是怎麼回事？
Now what the devil's all this about?
我沒得到答案是不會走的
I ain't moving until I get an answer.
抱歉, 哈利, 我不該來的
I'm sorry, Harry.
I shouldn't have come.
我低估了一些事情
I underestimated some things.
回答我的問題就好
Just answer the question.
這跟自由與和平有關, 哈利
It has to do
with freedom and peace, Harry.
而有些人兩者都不喜歡
And some people who don't like either.
我希望這值得那尾溜掉的鱒魚
Well, I sure hope
it's worth losing that damn trout.
他們還活著, 阿克斯特
They're still alive, Axminster.
-要把他們拉上來嗎？ -別管了
Shall we pick them up?
AXMINSTER: Forget them.
走吧
Move it.
有正事要辦
We got a job to do.
附近有林務站嗎？
Is there a ranger station around?
還是林火瞭望台、農場什麼的
How about a fire lookout,
a ranch, anything?
我想想, 艾福莫
Ah, let's see.
Evermore, uh, it's a little,
是個鳥不生蛋的小鎮
old nothing town, uh, half dead.
會有電話線路
Well, now they got a phone line.
有多遠？
How far is it?
10至12哩吧
Oh, it's ten to 12 miles.
在高地沙漠區
It's up in the high desert.
好, 我們走
All right. Let's move.
走那邊 我們會繞過山丘跟你會合
AXMINSTER: Go that way.
We'll swing around the hill and meet you.
好
CARSON: Right.
打從兩年前被灰熊追之後…
HARRY: Haven't done this much running
就沒這麼跑過了
since two winters ago when a grizzly was chasing me.
牠有抓到你嗎？
Did he catch you?
沒有, 牠追鵟追累了
HARRY: Nah, got tired trying to catch an old buzzard.
你在做什麼？停下來撿石頭？
Hey, what are you doing now?
Stop to collect rocks?
也許是那邊
CARSON: Maybe up that way.
好, 把他們逼出來
AXMINSTER: Okay, we'll flush them out.
看到什麼了嗎？
See anything?
我看到很多東西
MacGYVER: Oh, I see a lot of things.
有什麼是我感興趣的嗎？
Anything I'd be interested in?
有
兩輛吉普車分開
Yeah. Two jeeps splitting up.
其中一輛往這邊來了 但還要一陣子才會到
Only one's heading our way,
but he's gonna be
我想我們還有點時間
a while getting here, so I figure we got a little time.
做什麼？
To do what?
哈利
你忘了教過我 怎麼誘捕動物了嗎？
Harry, don't you remember teaching me all about decoys?
把這個裝滿樹枝如何？
Why don't you fill that up with branches?
對, 弄個假人
Oh, yeah, and make it look like a man.
我來看看能否 用這棵樹玩幾招
Now let's see if I can get this tree to do a few tricks.
沒看到他們往這邊來
AXMINSTER: No sign of them coming this way.
要繼續開嗎？
CARSON: Should I keep going?
我們該搞懂馬蓋先
AXMINSTER: We should figure out MacGyver.
再做決定
Then make a decision.
艾法、柯林、貝克, 聽到嗎？
Alpha, Colin, Baker,
do you read?
這是阿克斯特, 看到目標了嗎
This is Axminster.
Are targets in sight?
沒有
No, sir.
沒關係
反正是貓捉老鼠, 繼續走
No problem, it's just a little cat and mouse. Keep moving.
你們聽到命令了, 通話結束
You got your orders. Over and out.
好了嗎？
Okay?
往高地去
Head up to high ground.
對, 今天很適合打獵
AXMINSTER: Yeah, it's a nice day for hunting.
哈利？
Hey, Harry?
記得你以前告訴我 印第安人是怎麼作戰的嗎？
Remember you used to tell me about
how the Indians fought this way?
孩子
Bud...
我過去跟你說的很多事情
a lot of that stuff
I used to tell you is, uh, is stories.
都是故事而已
對, 不過很多都管用, 哈利
Yeah, well, a lot of it works, Harry.
( Jeep approaching )
( yelling )
可惡
Damn.
我還以為至少有車可以用了
Thought we'd at least get a free ride out of this.
看來得繼續跑了
Guess we keep on running.
那是阿克斯特, 快走
MacGYVER: That's Axminster. Let's get going.
阿克斯特 另一輛車掉到山坑裡了
BLACK: Axminster, the other jeep, down in the gully.
又兩個受傷 我們去把馬蓋先解決掉
AXMINSTER: Two more down.
Let's finish this MacGyver now.
我頭昏眼花了, 孩子
You getting lightheaded, bud?
松果？
Pinecones?
沒錯, 哈利
Sure, Harry.
試過丟一個到火裡…
Don't you remember ever throwing one in a fire?
會怎麼樣嗎？
What happens?
會炸開來
It kind of explodes.
沒錯
Yeah, that's right.
加點松脂, 就能做地雷了
Add a little pine pitch and you got the makings of a landmine.
大自然很偉大吧
Ain't Mother Nature grand?
你是要躲開他們 還是有什麼主意了？
HARRY: You just trying to stay above them
or you got some kind of an idea?
兩者都有
A little of both.
我可以的
No, I can manage!
等一下, 哈利
Hold it, Harry.
我想吉普車會從那裡…
I figure the Jeep'll come from there
往這裡來
right through here.
你在…
Well, what in the...?
該埋地雷了
Time to bury the landmine.
看到什麼了嗎？
HARRY: See something?
沒有, 但我聽到聲音了
MacGYVER: Nope, but I hear something.
該走了
HARRY: Ought to get a move on.
時間多得是
Ah, there's plenty of time.
你確定會成功？
You sure that'll work?
不
Nope.
孩子, 你還真會安慰人
Bud, you are a comfort.
他們來了
HARRY: Here they come.
快, 我們走
Come on, let's go.
我小時候會把松脂當口香糖
When I was a kid, I used to chew
pine pitch like it was gum.
味道還可以
It tasted all right, but it burned a lot better.
拿來燒更好
好
All right.
( rapid gunfire )
( grunting )
哈利？
Harry?
我沒事
I'm all right.
丟過去
Get him!
( yelling )
來吧, 哈利, 我們快走
Come on, Harry, let's get moving.
大家還好嗎？
AXMINSTER: Can anybody still move?
夠好到能抓馬蓋先了
CARSON: Yeah, good enough to find MacGyver.
看來我們也得走路了
BLACK: Looks like we're walking now, too.
不是走, 是跑
AXMINSTER: Not walk, run.
要他進黃泉
We'll run him right into the ground.
不要緊的
Well, that's okay.
只是小傷
I'm just dinged.
我注意到了
Yeah, so I noticed.
只是擦傷, 哈利
Just grazed you, Harry.
有可能更糟
Could've been worse, you know.
痛起來像很嚴重
Eh, hurts like worse.
放在裡面
Put that inside.
用力壓住
Put pressure on it.
你還好嗎？
You all right?
我們到了
We made it.
對
Yeah.
嘿…
HARRY: Hey!
所以…這就是艾福莫
MacGYVER: So... this is Evermore.
( coughs )
哈利
Harry, when was the last time you were here?
你上次來這裡是什麼時候？
太久了
Too long ago.
是個死城了
It's dead.
我猜我們也是
I guess we are, too.
哈利…
Harry? Harry! Harry!
該死的阿克斯特
Damn you, Axminster.
所以我倆在這鬼城
So, there we were in a ghost town, Harry and me.
哈利和我
我盡可能讓他舒服些
I tried to make him as comfortable as possible.
你在做什麼, 孩子？
What are you trying, bud?
那是愚人金
That's fool's gold.
有黃鐵礦
Which contains
pyrite-- iron sulfide.
硫化鐵
加點黏土混合起來 像是天然抗生素
Mixing it up with a little clay here
kind of makes a natural antibiotic.
看看你的傷怎麼樣了
Let's see what you got here.
你到底是做什麼的, 孩子？
Just what is it that you do, bud?
一點這個, 一點那個
Well, a little of this, a little of that.
( groans softly )
那麼…
Well, that... that sure explains it.
那就難怪了
你會沒事的, 哈利
You're going to be okay, Harry.
有想過掛個招牌當巫醫嗎？
Ever think of hanging out a shingle
as a medicine man?
我有話要說
I've got something to say.
我一直在躲你
I've avoided you.
知道為什麼嗎？
You know why?
我媽
Mom.
先是你外婆
First your grandmother.
然後是你媽
Then your mom.
當老天爺把她們帶走
When the good Lord took them,
我很傷心
I hurt.
我不願想起, 所以我…
I didn't want to be reminded,
so I just, uh, I just kept moving.
我就離開了
看到你…
Seeing you...
我很想你, 孩子
I've missed you, bud.
真可怕
Something terrible.
哈利
( softly ): Harry...
( sighing )
這真是很可悲的一幕
Well, that... sure was a sorry sight.
( sniffling )
夠了
Hey.
不准你說我外公壞話, 知道嗎
Don't you
ever badmouth my grandpa, you hear?
( chuckling )
( groaning )
我要找些東西來跟他們對抗 你說呢？
Look, I'm going to try and find some things
for us to fight with.
What do you say?
你真的認為 他們會找到這裡？
You really think they're going to find us here?
他們是職業殺手, 哈利
They're professionals, Harry.
他們會找到我們的
They'll find us.
哈利好好地休息了一晚
Harry had a good night's rest, but I didn't sleep at all.
但我完全沒睡
我知道天一亮 阿克斯特就會開始追蹤我們
I knew that, with first light,
Axminster would be tracking us again.
所以我得在那之前 做最好的防備
So, I had to build the best defense I could
before they got to us.
孩子
Hey, bud!
你在做什麼呢？
Mind telling me what you're doing?
我找到一些穀物屑
Yeah, found some grain dust.
好好利用就可以做很好的炸彈
Treat it right,
we got the makings of a pretty good bomb,
我確定
I'll betcha.
效果可能不錯
Might work good.
再弄點玄虛引他們來到 要爆炸的地方
Got a little parlor trick
to get them to come up close to where the explosion happens.
有時榖倉裡的穀物屑會爆炸
Sometimes you hear about floating grain dust
exploding inside a silo.
那叫自燃
It's called spontaneous combustion.
我則是刻意的
I'm going to do it on purpose.
而我發現哈利真是個好搭檔
And I found a real handy partner in Harry.
他想法就跟我一樣
He seemed to be talking just the way I was.
或說我的想法一直像他一樣
Or maybe I'd been thinking like him all along.
你的大爆炸只有一次機會, 孩子
HARRY: Only get one shot
with your exploding gadget, bud.
你有什麼打算, 哈利？
MacCGYVER: What you got in mind, Harry?
聲東擊西引他們過來
HARRY: A little remote control distraction.
保證讓那些呆子來這裡 收到大驚喜
Guaranteed to get them galoots
to come up real close for the big surprise.
孩子, 我從這裡可以像魔術師一樣
Hey, bud, I can play magician from over here!
忽隱忽現
Now you see it, now you don't-- and boom!
然後爆炸
好了, 這樣夠了
All right, that's enough.
已經在搖了 我可不想它倒在我頭上
It's shaking,
and I don't want it falling on my head.
訣竅是要讓那些呆瓜就定位
Real trick's going to be
getting those galoots in position.
如果他們不站在正下方 就行不通了
MacGYVER: If they aren't
right underneath it, it won't work.
你要去哪？
Where are you going?
過來, 我也有一招
HARRY: Come on.
I got a trick of my own.
這是什麼？松子？
What do you got, pine nuts?
我小時候會拿來玩
HARRY: Yeah, I used to have fun with them
when I was a kid.
把它們丟到火裡
I'd, uh, drop them in the fire,
看大家跳來跳去, 松子會爆開
and watch everybody jump, and they'd crack,
就像子彈一樣
and they'd go off like gunshots.
他們一直被你騙倒
Well, they've been falling
for your foolishness.
我想也來試試我自己的
I figured I'd try some of my own.
我想哈利開始喜歡這遊戲了
I think Harry was beginning to enjoy the game.
然而時間到了
And that's all the time we had.
( clanking )
( men yelling )
( loud popping )
( man grunts )
逮到他了
Got him good.
是啊
Yeah.
還有阿克斯特
We still have Axminster.
不過這次我們佔優勢了
Only this time, we got the odds.
對
Yeah.
Ow!
( grunting )
( gun cocking )
( gunshot )
再過去一點, 孩子
Try, try to move him over, bud.
( grunting )
就是現在, 孩子
Now, bud!
( yelling )
你還好嗎, 孩子？
You all right, bud?
我好得很, 哈利
I'm more than all right, Harry.
( groans )
Whew!
( both laugh )
你有打算要再來嗎？
You figuring on coming back this way?
一定會的
Count on it.
我會期待的
I'll look forward to it.
我也是
Me, too.
哈利
Hey, Harry...
你要抓到那尾鱒魚, 好嗎？
catch that big old trout, will you?
一定會的
Count on it.
好好保重, 孩子
Take care of yourself, bud.